# ANSELM MARIE

## Senior Software Engineer • UI/UX Designer

404-432-6815 @ anselmmariebusiness@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Senior Software Engineer Lead

03/2020 - 10/2023

#### Cricket Wireless

Atlanta

- · Mitigated production issues by implementing code standards and processes, resulting in a 35% decrease in bug reports.
- Led a cross-functional team of developers and designers to implement new functionality.
- Mentored junior and intern developers, resulting in a 20% increase in productivity.
- Revamped tech stack, using React, Redux, TypeScript, etc., resulting in improved performance and scalability by 30%.
- Conducted interviews with designers and developers as part of the team selection
- Developed a comprehensive design system with my team, integrating UI elements and commonly used utilities for a streamlined workflow.
- Oversee agile/kanban workload, monitor JIRA tickets, and address the tech debt
- Used React, Angular, Node.js, TypeScript, Webpack/Vite, Module Federation, Git, Storybook, Nx/Monorepo, BugSnag, Full Story, Tailwind, SCSS, REST APIs, Figma.

Sr. Associate - Projects

01/2020 - 02/2020

Macy's

Senior Application Developer

08/2019 - 01/2020

Atlanta

Alpharetta **ADP** Developed and maintained features for both desktop and mobile applications at ADP.

Used React, Redux, Angular, SCSS, LESS, and TypeScript.

### Senior Developer Manager

12/2017 - 01/2019

Cricket Wireless Atlanta

- · Established and nurtured robust connections with stakeholders.
- I spearheaded the frontend development and design for an application, guiding it from inception to completion. The notable success of this endeavor was recognized with the receipt of an "AT&T Service Excellence Award," underscoring the impact of this initiative.
- Used ES6+, Webpack, Babel, jQuery, Bootstrap, and REST APIs.

### Senior Application Developer

12/2013 - 12/2017

#### **Cricket Wireless**

Atlanta

- Enhancement and ongoing development of the Cricket Wireless website, impacting over 5 million monthly visitors.
- Developed numerous internal applications catering to various departments within the organization.
- Used ES6+, Webpack, Babel, ¡Query, Bootstrap, and REST APIs.

Interactive Developer

06/2011 - 11/2013

Corporate Reports, Inc.

Buckhead

Lead Web Designer/Developer

07/2009 - 06/2011

CoStar Group, Inc.

Norcross

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Graphic Design

American InterContinental University

### 01/2005

### **SUMMARY**

With over a decade of experience in frontend and backend development, complemented by a solid understanding of UI/UX principles, I am a resultsoriented professional. My expertise extends to leadership, where I excel in guiding teams, overseeing projects, and crafting strategic roadmaps to achieve success. Constantly adapting to emerging technologies, I am committed to continuous learning and growth.

### **SKILLS**

React · React Native · Expo · Next.js ·

PostgreSQL · JWT · Authorization ·

Design System · CI/CD · UI/UX ·

Leadership · Agile/Kanban

### **HOBBY PROJECT**

### Cosmikata

02/2023 - Present

Tucker, GA

Creating an application tailored for cosplayers and cosmakers, I am developing it by incorporating a range of industry-leading practices and standards accumulated throughout my professional journey.

My approach to constructing this application involves:

- React
- React Native
- Expo
- Tamagui
- Next.js
- Node.is
- PostgreSQL
- Prisma and SQL Query
- Nx Monorepo
- CI/CD: GitHub Actions
- Figma